♪Looking in the mirror,
my temples have turned white♪
♪Taking off the hairpins and makeup,
shedding the disguise♪
♪A cold face♪
♪With two lines of tears♪
♪If an actor could gain pity♪
♪The audience offers sincere words♪
♪Perhaps the story could be changed♪
♪The storyteller says♪
♪This mortal world is full of turmoil♪
♪Within sight but beyond reach♪
♪Yet I still don't want to give up♪
♪Don't let the memory be hollowed out♪
♪Don't make me ridiculous♪
♪Some vows turn into smoke
and fade away♪
♪Even the leaves know when autumn comes,
but you don't even know me♪
♪Imprisoned in plight,
yet still full of passion♪
♪I mock this absurd and entangled love♪
♪How can I bear to let go♪
=Whispers of Southern Song=
=Episode 2=
Master gave me this.
He is dead now,
and I just keep it as a memento.
Please give it back to me.
Mr. Rong, you'd better tell the truth.
Otherwise, no matter
who's protecting you,
I can make you disappear without a trace
in the Governor Mansion.
I am telling the truth.
You are used to killing innocents.
If you want to kill me, just do it.
Stop talking nonsense.
Bang!
Mr. Rong, you have a delicate face,
but you got the courage of a man.
Tell me, where is the real Buddha Head?
It's a secret that can save my life.
How could I tell you that easily?
Save your life?
You should beg me
to leave you a whole corpse.
If I remember correctly,
you are not the one in charge here.
If I tell the Governor my secret
to pledge my loyalty,
I might even be able
to trade it for your life.
Pledge loyalty?
In my foster father's eyes,
you are nothing but an ant.
Then kill me.
Let the Buddha Head be buried with me
and the entire Rongqing Troupe forever,
and never come out again.
Given how much the Governor
values the Buddha Head,
no matter how foolish you are,
I bet you wouldn't want to perish with me.
They say actors are heartless.
I have kept your life until now.
Yet you're showing no gratitude,
even going back on your word.
(No.)
(Killing him alone is not enough
to avenge the Rongqing Troupe.)
(What I want is the annihilation
of the entire Governor Mansion.)
Miss Jiang, you can't go in.
Move aside!
I am Young Marshal's future wife.
How dare you stop me?
Mr. Rong.
You came at the perfect time.
You came to deliver medicine
to a man's room alone this late.
What's wrong? Why are you so scared
upon seeing your future husband?
Are you here to have an affair,
instead of delivering medicine?
I was just worried about
whether Mr. Rong could perform tomorrow.
If not,
the Governor Mansion might suffer.
What are you doing here so late?
I also came to check on
Mr. Rong's wounds.
I don't want him to die silently
in the Governor Mansion.
But with you caring about him,
he probably won't die that soon.
Mr. Rong.
- Mr. Rong, you...
- Since the medicine has been delivered,
why are you still here?
Do you want
to spend a night here with me?
(Master.)
(Once I finish this last performance,
I will come join you)
(and reunite with others
of Rongqing Troupe.)
(Governor Mansion)
Miss Jiang, today you and I
will share the stage?
The first performance of yours I watched
was "A Garden Stroll".
At that time, I thought,
if I had the chance to perform with you,
I would have no regrets in my life.
Miss Jiang,
today is not a good chance.
If there is another chance,
I will invite you to perform together.
We could perform for three whole days.
Mr. Rong,
today might be the last time
we see each other, so please indulge me.
Miss Jiang, why do you say that?
After you were taken away yesterday,
I went to plead with my father.
He demanded that I never see you again
and marry Young Marshal Xu obediently.
I agreed.
Because this is the only way
I could think of to save you.
I've checked it out.
During the noon banquet, all the guards
will be in the front courtyard,
and only one guard at the back gate.
Take this, and no one
will dare to stop you.
(Qian Sihai, Hu Feng)
For this business to last long,
(Special Envoys of Xiaosheng Society)
I have to rely on you two.
Cheers!
Great working with you.
Foster Father.
I'll go check on the stage preparations.
Mm.
You two wanted to watch the performance
of Mr. Rong. I bet he won't fail you.
This shipment of artifacts seems
to be missing what the Japanese wanted.
No business today, just relax.
Alright.
No way.
If I escape,
you will definitely be implicated.
I'm about to marry the Young Marshal.
They won't do anything to me.
But you,
if you don't leave now,
you will lose your life.
I don't deserve you risking your life.
Put it here.
Inside that chest
is a set of servant's clothes.
During the set change
after the third act, I'll perform.
You'll put on these clothes
and take the chance to escape.
(But I have something I must do,
and I can't leave yet.)
I'll send men to guard the back gate.
Rong Xiaonan can't escape.
No.
Let him escape.
This Rong Xiaonan is very cunning.
He would rather die than talk.
But if we let him escape,
send someone to follow him. Maybe we can
find the Jade Buddha Head's whereabouts.
Yes.
By the way,
as per your previous instructions,
we have replaced everyone
near the west wing rooms
where the Xiaosheng Society is
with our own men.
I need to find out
what business Foster Father is doing
with Xiaosheng Society.
Search carefully.
A list.
(Inventory List)
So the business Foster Father
and Xiaosheng Society are doing
is artifacts smuggling.
Young Lady.
Mr. Qian,
pleasure working with you.
Likewise.
♪Spring, oh spring♪
♪I must linger with you♪
♪How to pass the time
when spring is gone♪
♪Such weather♪
(Mr. Rong.)
(I hope we could meet again after this.)
(Don't worry.)
(No matter what happens,
I will definitely hold them back)
(to ensure you leave safely.)
♪As if it were fate♪
♪Deliberately playing tricks♪
♪We miss each other♪
♪Creating a turbulent drama♪
♪And a bizarre♪
♪Anonymous legend♪
♪The plot twists and turns♪
♪Play out over and over again♪
♪Waiting to be discarded♪
♪And you are like a moth to the flame♪
♪Refuse to submit♪
♪I can't bear to blame you♪
♪There are always too many♪
♪Helpless situations♪
♪Overwhelmed by time♪
♪Even if I have questions♪
♪I harbor desires♪
♪Nowhere to find answers♪
♪People come and go♪
♪I'm still all alone♪
♪Wandering around♪
♪Fortunate to have you with me♪
♪Go through the entanglement♪
♪If longing♪
♪Turns into dust and smoke♪
♪How can I be at ease♪
♪Having walked through prosperous times♪
♪And travelled around the world♪
♪Scars all over me♪
♪If longing never fades♪
♪Burns still hot♪
♪Let it turn into dust and smoke♪
♪After half a lifetime of loneliness♪
♪In the next life♪
♪Entangle with you again♪